Jamison, C. Collection of United Mineworkers of America Convention Papers and Audio-Visual Materials 5536
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
C. Jamison Collection of United Mineworkers of America Convention Papers and Audio-Visual Materials
1976
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Jamison, C.
United Mineworkers of America (UMWA)
5536
1.61 cubic feet
1.6 linear ft.
Records (documents), audiovisual materials.
Reports, speeches, and audiorecordings from the United Mineworkers of America convention, 1976.
5659412
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, April 17, 2014
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 18, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The United Mineworkers of America (UMWA) was founded in Columbus, Ohio in 1890. In 1967, W.A. "Tony" Boyle was the President of the UMWA.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of reports, speeches, and audiorecordings from the United Mineworkers of America convention, 1976.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Jamison, C.; United Mine Workers of America.
5659412
- Background, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Collective Bargaining Committee report, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Legislative and Political Action Committee (COMPAC) report, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Constitutional committee, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Committee on Credentials, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Resolution to reschedule the election of international officers in 1977, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Health and retirement committee report, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Health and safety committee report, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Organizing committee, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Releases, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Resolutions, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Rules, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Report of the International Secretary-Treasurer, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Speeches, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Audio recordings of the UMWA convention, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Scope and Contents
  10 audio cassette tapes
- UMWA Convention, Oct. 1976 - Harry Patricks Conference (Box 2, Folder 1)
- UMWA Convention, Oct. 1976 - Constitution Comm. - Resolution to Reschedule Presidential Election, Passed (Box 3, Folder 1)
- UMWA Convention, Oct. 1976 - Process of Going through Health and Safety Comm. Report - Procedures (Box 4, Folder 1)
- UMWA Convention, Oct. 1976 - Health & Safety Committee - Sept. 25 - Red Scare - Communist (Box 5, Folder 1)
- UMWA Convention, Oct. 1976 - Constitution Comm. Art. 5, Sec. 5,7,13,27,29 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- UMWA Convention, Oct. 1976 - Art. 14, Sec. 2 UMWA Purchase Stocks Collective Barg. Comm. I (Box 7, Folder 1)
- UMWA Convention, Oct. 1976 - Constitution Comm. - Organizers Dept. - Art. 5, Sec. 4 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- UMWA Convention, Oct. 1976 - V.P. Trbovich Statement - Delegation Reaction and Comments (Box 9, Folder 1)
- UMWA Convention, Oct. 1976 - Willie Freeman, 9/27/76 - Bluefield, W. VA. (Box 10, Folder 1)
- UMWA Convention, Oct. 1976 - Cincinnati - Keynote Address - Irving Bluesyon & UAW State of Union - Arnold Miller (Box 11, Folder 1)